Sincro: wyxchari
Oh, splendid! Splendid!
You've got a very good band there, Barney.
喔，太棒了太棒了！你这个乐队真不错，Barney
Thank you, Pilot
谢谢你，领航员
Mind you, I don't say you'll come first at the festival,
but never say die, hmm, what?/
Nothing succeeds like success, ha!
"If at first you don't succeed...?"
“如果一开始你没有成功...”
"... Try, try, try again!"
“...再，再，再来一次”
That's right.
就是这样
Stop him! Don't let him get out!
拦住他！别让他跑出去了！
What's the matter?
什么事情？
Medok!
Let me go!
放开我！
Medok! This is very foolish of you Medok.
It's for your own good.
Medok！你真是太蠢了，这是为了你自己好
Out of my way!
别挡我道！
He's far too dangerous to be allowed to escape.
他太危险了，不能让他逃走
Get after him!
You should have stopped him!
去追他！你们应该拦住他的！
What happened, Ola?
发生了什么，Ola？
He refused treatment in front of my guards,
so I dismissed them...
他拒绝在我的警卫面前接受治疗，于是我遣散了他们...
- and he made a dash for it.
- Well get after him.
- 他就趁机冲出来了  - 那去追他
He must not get away!
不能让他跑了！
Hey!
嘿！
Oh! Oh, Ben! For goodness sake!
噢！噢，Ben！天可怜见！
Well, what's the big stick for Jamie?
Nothing's happened yet.
Have you no sense? Have you forgot
what we saw on that time scanner?
你没有感觉吗？你已经忘了我们在时间扫描仪上面看见的东西？
(通过时间扫描仪可以瞥见未来, 最开始出现在《月球基地》一集)
Don't, it was horrible.
别，那太可怕了
Aye, well, I'll not being left without nothing
to defend ourselves with.
I'm afraid you're wasting your time, Jamie.
我觉得你恐怕是在浪费自己的时间，Jamie
Why?
怎么说？
Unless I'm very much mistaken,
these creatures are so big...
除非我错得离谱，这些怪物如此之大...
they're going to see us long before we see them.
在我们看见它们之前，它们就先看见我们了
Look out Jamie!
小心，Jamie！
Hang on, mate, I'll get him!
坚持，伙计，我来fixme
Ben!
Sit on top of him!
What are you doing?_!
你在做什么？
Ben, are you all right?
Ben，你没事吧？
We don't know who you are, strangers,
but we are grateful.
虽然我们不认识，异乡人，但我们很感激
Medok is one of our last patients in the Colony.
Medok 是这个殖民地仅有的几个病人之一
We've done our best for him
but he gets worse day by day...
我们已经为他尽了最大的努力, 但他的情况一天比一天差
I wasn't informed you were
travelling across our territory.
我没有收到信息说你们正在我们的领土上旅行
Hurry back to the Colony
and tell the Pilot what's happened.
赶紧回到殖民地，告知领航员这里发生的情况
Pilot?
领航员？
Yes, the Pilot of our colony. No doubt
he will want to thank you in person.
是的，我们殖民地的领航员。毫无疑问他会想要亲自感谢你
Tie him up tighter. Come on, tighter!
I don't want any more trouble with him.
把他绑紧点。使劲，紧点！我不想让他再惹麻烦了
Come on, I'll show you myself. Get out of...
Er, uh, any good asking where we are?
呃，我想问问我们是在哪儿？
Well, according to my calculations
we're, er, certainly in the future and,
根据我的计算，我们是在...当然是在未来，而且...
- er, on a planet very like the Earth.
- How do you know?
- 在一个跟地球非常相似的星球上  - 你怎么知道？
I don't know. I'm guessing.
我不知道，只是猜测
My name is Ola. I am the Chief of Police.
我名叫 Ola，是这里的警察局长
That sounds very important.
这听起来是个重要人物
Oh, it's a very responsible job.
I take my instructions from our Control centre.
噢，这是个很需要责任的工作。我听从我们控制中心的指令
Oh, it all works very well, as you will see.
Please follow me.
噢，它运作得很好，你们会看到的。请跟我来
Oh, thank you.
噢，谢谢你
Ah, not too tight l?
It's bad for the blood pressure.
啊，不要太紧了。这样对血压不好
"Run, run, run, run...
“跑跑跑跑...
Run, run, run, run!
跑跑跑跑！
Thank you shift...
Number one!
Pilot, these are the strangers
that have helped us.
领航员，这就是刚才帮助了我们的几位异乡人
Very well, Ola. I will look after our guests.
很好，Ola。我来招待我们的客人
You will no doubt wish to take care of poor Medok.
You may leave.
毫无疑问你想要去照顾可怜的Medok。你可以走了
Well, our thanks to you and welcome!
我们感谢你们，也欢迎你们的到来！
You are indeed a brave man
to tackle someone as disturbed as Medok.
你真是一个勇敢的人，能对付像 Medok 这样失常的人
Well, it was nothing.
Anyone would have done the same.
这没什么，谁都会这么做的
Well this is gay! Why all the music?
这里很欢乐啊，为什么到处都是音乐？
Oh, we regulate our day by music.
噢，我们通过音乐来调节我们的一天
Oh.
哦
Yes...
是的
...and now my friends, I suggest you
take advantage of our refreshing department.
现在我的朋友们, 我建议你们利用一下我们的充能部门
Oh, lead me to it mate. I'm starving.
哦，带我去吧朋友，我饿死了
Oh, you will eat later.
Here we revive the weary body.
哦，你可以稍后再吃东西。这是我们让疲劳的身体恢复精力的地方
Oh.
哦
Keep your eyes skinned.
Why? What's the matter?
为什么？什么情况？
Well, they're a weird sort of folk.
I don't know that I understand them.
Come along in, my friends, It's just through _ there.
Pilot! Pilot! Control wish you to call them immediately./
领航员！领航员！管理员期望你立即跟他联系
They wish to welcome our guests.
他们想要给我的客人一个欢迎仪式
Oh, but of course.
噢，这是当然
Switch on please, my dear.
请打开吧，亲爱的
Hey, who's that? He looks smashing.
That's our Controller.
这是我们的管理员
We wish to welcome joyfully the visitors to our colony. /57
We are very grateful to them.
They have performed a valuable service. /01
The Colony is to make our guests happy
and contented during their stay. /06
Welcome again, friends. Now, back to work, everyone!
Well that's great! I'm really going to enjoy myself.
那太好了！我还真想一个人待会儿
Splendid! And now my good friends,
let me put you into the hands of our supervisor, Barney.
太棒了！现在我的好朋友们，我就把你们交到我们的监管员 Barney 手里了
Dear old Barney, everybody calls him.
亲爱的老 Barney，每个人都这么叫他
Well, thank you Pilot.
哦，谢谢你领航员
And I must leave you for... work calls you know,
and hard work never hurt anybody.
我必须让你...工作在呼唤你知道吧, 努力工作总是不会有坏处的
Till later!
Delighted to see you. Delighted to have you with us.
很高兴见到你们，很高兴你们跟我们在一起。
Now you have a complete choice of all our treatments.
现在你们可以选择我们所有的休闲方式
We have steam baths, beauty treatments, perhaps a massage. /36.9
我们有蒸汽浴，美容护理，还有按摩。
You sir, of course, would like your clothes cleaned.
先生你，当然了，可以要求把衣服清洗干净
And there's sunlight treatment, moonlight treatment,
sparkling and effervescent sprays...
还有日光护理, 月光护理, 起泡喷剂...
I feel perfectly all right as I am, thank you.
我现在就觉得非常好，谢谢你了
Ah, go on Doctor. Don't be such a drag.
It all looks super. Please, may I have a shampoo?
啊, 去啊博士。不要这样的勉强。一切都超级棒的。请给我洗发水好吗？
Shampoo, of course, for the young lady.
当然，洗发香波提供给年前女士
Thanks very much.
非常感谢
And for the young gentlemen, our very
latest treatment in our cubicles over there.
对于年轻的绅士，那边是本包间提供的最后一道护理
Me? Oh, hey, you're not going to do that to me. I'm no lassie.
我吗？哦，嘿，你可别对我来这个，我可不是个姑娘
It's no good, Jamie, the lassies have got you!
And believe me mate, I'm not going to struggle.
没用的，Jamie，姑娘们抓住你了。而且相信我朋友，我可不打算挣扎
And now sir, for you...
现在，到你了先生
Oh, very nice. Very nice indeed. You must certainly be
the most beautiful young lady in our Colony  /17.9
哦，很好，真的非常好。你肯定是我们殖民地最年轻漂亮的女士
and are quite sure to be elected our next beauty president.
肯定可以赢得下一届的选美冠军
Thank you very much.
太感谢你了
Oh, not at all. It's all part of our service.
哦，完全不用。这都是我们服务的一部分
To your liking sir?
你还喜欢吗，先生？
Ah, marvellous. Like being at anchor in the Med.
Some protective oils for our guests and a little suntan.
给我们的客人来点防晒霜, 再让他们晒黑点
Ha ha! This is the life.
哈哈！这才是生活
Hey mister, would you call the ladies off?
I'm frightened what they might do to me.
嘿先生, 你能把女士们叫走吗？我有点害怕她们会对我做点什么
But you look charming, sir. Charming.
但你看起来太有魅力了, 先生, 太有魅力
That's what I'm frightened of.
我就是害怕这个
Please get me out of here! I'm done to a turn!
请带我离开这里！fixme
Clothes reviver.
衣服翻新器
My clothes don't need reviving!
我的衣服不需要翻新！
Oh, while we're about it, sir... and off.
噢, 我们正要...先生..关掉了
Oh, Doctor. You look gorgeous!
噢, 博士, 你看来很炫！
Oh, my shoes!
哦, 我的鞋子！
Oh, they're fantastic. You can see your face in them.
它们太亮了．你都能在里面看见你的脸
Precisely. Who wants to see their face
in a pair of suede shoes?
的确．谁想要用鞣皮鞋子来当镜子？
What's this one?
这一个是什么？
Oh, that, sir, is our rough and tumble machine,
for toning up the muscles.
哦, 先生, 那个是我们的打斗机器, 增强肌肉用的
Exactly what I need!
正是我需要的
Full on!
马力全开！
Oh, but no, sir! No!
噢, 不要, 先生！别这样！
Turn it off.
关掉它
Come out of it!
出来吧
Come out of it, Doctor.
出来吧, 博士
Oh, oh, I feel better. Oh, that's what I need.
噢, 噢, 我觉得好点了．噢, 我正需要这个
Oh, you look smashing. You really do.
You look like a prince./
噢, 你看起来很兴奋, 真的．看起来像个王子
Jamie that's super. It really is.
Jamie, 那个很厉害, 真的很厉害
Come on, move back! This prisoner's not to be trusted.
He's violent and suffering from delusions.
快点, 回来！那个囚犯不可信, 他很暴力而且还有幻觉
I'm not the one suffering from delusions, it's you!
All of you!/?
我可以不是受幻觉影响的人, 你才是！你们全部都是！
You don't know what's happening in this Colony!
你们不知道这个殖民地在发生什么！
Be quiet Medok!
安静, Medok!
There's only one way to silence me, Ola.
只有一种方法让我安静, Ola
Medok, old fellow, it's Questa. Remember me?
What's happened to you?
Medok, 老伙计, 我是 Questa, 记得我吗？你怎么了？
It's no good. You can't reason with him.
这样没用的．你没法跟他讲道理的
Just a minute. He's an old friend. One of the best.
请等一下．他是一个老朋友, 最好的那种
Ha!
哈！
He's as cheerful as any of us.
Medok, what's happened to you?/?
他以前跟我们一样快活, Medok, 你身上发生了什么？
What's all this about you seeing things?
说你有幻视, 这是在说什么？
I don't see things Questa, you fool!
我没有幻视, Questa, 你个傻瓜！
There are things... horrible things... creatures,
infesting this camp at night.
有一些东西...可怕的东西...有一些生物, 在晚上侵袭这个营地
That's enough! Have you seen the Pilot?
够了！你见过领航员了吗？
He's with the strangers. I've no idea where they are.
他跟那几个异乡人在一起．我不知道他们在哪儿
Back to work! Shift rest is over!
No time to be lost! The Colony needs you!/?
回去工作！轮班休息已经结束了！没有时间可以浪费！殖民地需要你！
Preparation to be made for tonight's reception
- a welcome for the strangers!
还要准备今晚招待会呢 - 要为那些异乡人准备一个迎新会
A reception tonight! A Colony party!
今晚有招待会！全殖民地欢庆会！
Medok, join in with the rest of us, like you used to.
Medok, 加入我们一起来吧, 就像以前一样
It will be fun for all!
将是所有人的fixme
You hear that Medok, fun for all.
你听到了吧 Medok, 大家都很高兴
All right! Have fun while you can,
before they crawl all over you!
算了吧！就尽情玩乐吧, 趁着你们还能, 趁着它们还没有从你们头上爬过！
That's enough! Right, get back all of you.
不许胡说了！好了, 你们都回去吧
There you are. I wondered what had happened to you.
起来吧．我想知道你发生了什么情况
I don't know you. You don't belong here.
我不认识你, 你不属于这里
Do you belong here?
你属于这里吗？
No, not any more.
不, 不再是了
We don't talk to him. He sees things. Come on Medok.
我们不要跟他说话, 他有幻视．来吧 Medok
Can I help you?
有什么可以帮助你的？
What? Oh, no. No, it's all right, thank you./?
什么？哦, 不, 不用．没事的, 谢谢
I... I just thought I'd dropped something, that's all.
我...我只是觉得我掉了东西, 仅此而已
Ha! What's _?
哈！什么东西？
Shh, I'm going to set you free.
嘘, 我正打算放了你
Just hold still a minute. There we are. One more.
暂时不要动．这样．还有一个
Don't bother to say thank you./?
没必要说谢谢
Now, tell me something about these things
that you see, hmm?
现在, 告诉我关于你所看到的东西, 嗯？
Do they, for instance, appear to
crawl slowly over the ground?
比如说, 它们是不是看起来是在地上爬行的？
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Oh, just wondered that's all.
噢, 只是好奇而已
Listen!
听！
I don't hear anything.
我什么也没听见
Someone's coming.
有人来了
It's all right, I won't let them hurt you.
没事的, 我不会允许他们伤害你
Get out of my way!
别挡我的路！
Why don't you listen to me?
你怎么不听我说呢？
I am not being caught!
我不想被抓住！
Stop him! Don't let him escape!
拦住他！别让他逃走了！
How did he get away? Who's responsible?
他怎么逃脱的？谁的责任？
What happened?
发生了什么？
I... I told him he wouldn't get hurt
and he wouldn't believe me.
我...我跟他说他不会受到伤害的, 但他不相信我
You mean you let him go?
你是说, 是你放他走的？
Well, no, not exactly.
哦, 不是, 不全是
He let the prisoner escape.
That is a crime in this Colony.
他放走了囚犯．这在殖民地是犯罪
For that, men must work in the pit. Guard!
为此, 他必须进入地窖(fixme)去工作．警卫！
You can't touch him. He doesn't know your laws!
你不能碰他, 他不知道你们的法律！
Er, that's true, Ola. He is a stranger here.
呃, 那倒是真的, Ola．他是个异乡人
There's something else you're forgetting gentlemen -
I set free someone that we caught in the first place.
还有些事情你们忘了, 先生们 - 我放走的人之前是我们抓住的
True - a reasonable point of view, Ola.
也是真的 - 这个观点挺有道理, Ola
Medok is dangerous. He should have never let him go./?
Medok 很危险．他无论如何不应该放走他的
The Colony will be petrified
when they know he's out there in the night.
整个殖民地的人都会惴惴不安的, 如果他们知道夜里他还在外面
Well, send your patrol after him.
He can't have got far.
好吧, 派你的巡逻队去追他．他不可能跑远的
He can run you know. He's got legs.
He doesn't have to crawl over the ground.
他能跑你知道吗, 他有脚．他不必在地上爬着走
Why did you say that?
你为什么这么说？
Why, no reason. No reason at all.
为什么？没有为什么．完全没有原因
Anyone who spreads that kind of rumour in this Colony
will find himself in the hospital for correction.
任何人在殖民地散播这种谣言, 结果都会发现自己在医院里进行矫正
Oh... oh, that's where Medok is, is it?
噢...噢, 那就是 Medok 待的地方, 是吗？
I think, Doctor, you will understand more about Medok
if you talk to some of the people who knew him best.
我觉得, 博士, 如果你跟最熟悉 Medok 的人多聊聊, 你会更加了解他的
Pilot, I think...
领航员, 我觉得...
Now take the strangers to the labour centre Ola.
现在带这些异乡人到劳动中心去, Ola
See they learn something about us.
Please, go with him.
确保他们对我们多一些了解．请, 跟他走吧
Oh, well thank you.
哦, 好吧, 谢谢你
What is it?
什么事？
Nothing, come on.
没什么, 快点
This is your Controller speaking.
There is no need for alarm.
这里是你们的管理员在讲话．没有必要惊慌
You may all continue your work and play,
confident that the best is being done for you.
你们全都可以继续工作或者娱乐, 相信给你们准备的都是最好的
But our unfortunate companion Medok
has been allowed to escape.
但我们不幸的同伴 Medok 被人放走了
Emergency Patrols two and three are
now searching the Colony
紧急巡逻队二号三号正在搜索
and he is sure to be caught before it is dark.
肯定可以在天黑前抓住他
Now return to your work and play
with fresh heart and renewed energy!
现在回到你们工作和娱乐中去吧, fixme
They got that bloke all over the place
like a blinking politician.
他们这里到处都有那个家伙, 像个闪耀的政客一样
He is our controller. We are always pleased to see him.
He brings us encouragement.
他是我们的管理员．我们很乐意见到他．他给我们鼓励
Oh, he's not a politician then!
噢, 那他不是一个政客
Number nine shift to stand by.
Leader to report to Youth Centre.
第九班次请做好准备．队长到青年中心报到
Work shift ready to leave.
工作班次准备离开
"We're happy to work,
"我们乐于工作
Happy to play,
乐于娱乐
That's a nice wee tune Doctor.
这个小调挺不错, 博士
Yeah, if you happen to like work.
是, 前提是你确实很喜欢工作
It's a privilege to work for the Colony.
在殖民地工作是一项特权
Shift leader reporting: Shift number nine,
all present and correct.
班次队长报告：第九班次, 全部到齐且正常
Good. You're the first of the night shift.
很好．你是夜间班次的第一个
Uh, what do ye do then? Farming or fishing?
哈, 你们做什么呢？农耕还是钓鱼？
We work very hard here.
我们在这里很努力地工作
Yes, but what do you do?
是, 但你们具体做什么？
We tap and refine gas.
我们采集并提炼瓦斯
For heating?
为了供热？
No, we use it for many things.
The Colony depends on it.
不, 我们用在很多方面．殖民地依赖于它
It's absolutely essen...
这东西绝对重要...
Emergency! Quick, give me that! Come on!
紧急情况！快, 把那个给我！快点！
Accident! Stand by, oxygen supply.
出事故了！准备氧气供应
Take them away. Any other losses?
把他们带走, 还有其它损失吗？
Two with gas sickness. Come on.
有两个被瓦斯喷晕了, 快点
What happened?
发生了什么事？
Their work. It can't be helped.
The work must be done.
他们的工作．fixme．工作必须完成
Do you hear that, Doctor?
你听到了吗, 博士？
Where's he gone?
他去哪儿了？
Shh! I saw you.
嘘！我看见你了
Get out!
出去！
Oh, that's not very polite.
I was interested in what you were saying.
哦, 那可不太礼貌．我对你之前的话很感兴趣
Who else knows I'm here?
还有谁知道我在这里？
No one. Why should I tell them?
没谁．我为什么要告诉他们？
Now these creatures - have you seen them clearly?
What do they look like?
现在说说那些怪物 - 你看清楚它们了吗？它们是什么样子的？
What has it to do with you?
这跟你有什么关系？
Well, I'm interested. What do they look like?
哦, 我感兴趣．它们是什么样子的？
All right. If you really want to know.
好吧, 如果你非想知道．
It's hard to say. They move at night, in the dark.
不太好说．它们在晚上移动, 在暗处
And look horrible. Creatures... like giant insects.
而且看起来很吓人．那些怪物...就像巨型的虫子
With big claws?
带有大螯？
Yes, that's it.
是的, 就是它
You've seen them in the Colony?
你在殖民地见过它们？
Oh yes.
是的
Has anyone else seen them?
还有其他人见到吗？
A few, but they've lock them up in the correction hospital.
有几个, 但他们都被关起来了, 关在矫正医院
Why do they do that?
他们为什么那么干？
Control tells them to.
They'll put me back there when they catch me.
管理员让他们干的．等他们抓到我, 也会把我放到那里去的
And they'll put you back there for helping me.
而且他们会把你放到那里去帮助我
Doctor! Doctor!
博士！博士！
Go on! Quickly! They're looking for you!
继续！快点！他们在看着你们呢！
Doctor!
博士！
But we searched there, I'm sure.
但我们搜过那里了, 我确定
Aye.
是
Were you looking for me?
你们是在找我吗？
Where have you been?
你去哪里了？
I'm just looking around, that's all.
我只是四周看看, 仅此而已
It's dangerous to go off on your own after dark.
天黑之后一个人乱走是很危险的
Oh, I'm used to the dark. I like it.
哦, 我已经习惯了黑夜了．我喜欢它
We're confined to rest cubicles at night
by order of Control.
夜间我们得待在休息间里面, 这是管理员的命令
Anyone who wanders around the Colony at night...
may be killed.
任何人如果在夜间在殖民地闲逛...可能会被杀
Curfew time. All personnel not on duty
must retire to quarters.
宵禁时间到了．所有不在值班的人员必须返回住处
Do you hear that?
你们听到了吗？
Emergency patrols two and three to remain on duty.
紧急巡逻队二号和三号继续原任务
Work shifts to remain at their posts until dawn.
工作班次人员继续在原岗位直到黎明
Visitors to retire for the night to
the refreshing department.
访客们夜间退回到休息室
That's you. You're confined here.
说你们呢．你们被限制待这里了
Here we are, Doctor.
我们到了, 博士
Your young friends are in their rooms over there.
你的年轻朋友们都在那边, 在他们自己的房间里了
Thank you.
谢谢你
I, er, I hope you sleep well.
我, 呃, 我期望你睡个好觉
Oh, I'm sure I will. Thank you. Goodnight.
噢, 我肯定会的．谢谢你．晚安
Goodnight, Doctor.
晚安, 博士
It is now dark. No one will go outside into the Colony.
A dangerous man is in hiding.
现在天黑了．谁都不能出去在殖民地乱跑．有一个危险人物还躲藏着
Our patrols have orders to shoot on sight.
Happy sleep time everybody.
我们的巡逻队收到了格杀勿论的命令．各位睡个好觉
And the same to you!
对你也是一样！
I'll have a look over there.
我要过去那边看一眼
It's all right. It's me. Stay where you are.
没事的, 是我．待在原地别动
Why are you back?
你回来做什么？
Don't move.
别动
Have a look in those new houses they're building.
看看他们正在建设的新房子
He's coming! We'll have to get out!
他来了！我们必须出去！
Wait! If he comes in this way, we'll go out the back.
等等！如果他从这边来, 我们就从外面回去
If he comes in the back, we'll go out here.
如果他从后面过来, 我们就从这里出去
He's coming... to the front of the house.
他来了...走房子的前面来的
Over here. I heard something.
这里．我听到了什么
All right. Go back.
好吧, 回去
You can't stay here.
你们不能待在这里
I'll try to create a diversion.
我去试试把他引开
No, they'll kill you!
不, 他们会杀死你的！
Do as I tell you.
按我告诉你的做
Thanks.
谢谢
Go on. Go on.
继续, 继续
All right, we'll go through this opening
when I give the word.
好吧, 等我发话, 我们从这个门进去
Right. Now!
好, 走！
No, look. Out there.
不, 看, 那边
I don't see anything.
我什么也没看见
In that patch of moonlight. I told you I'd seen them!
在那边月光下．我说过我见过它们的！